Timothy Payne Jr.

171 Lawnside Ave. Collingswood, NJ 08108 • (908) 331-1913

timothy.v.payne.jr@gmail.com ● linkedin.com/in/timothypaynejr ● https://github.com/TimothyVirgil

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - DATA

Senior Software Engineer with experience owning and delivering software data products. I have spent most of my recent work time building data applications on the Azure ecosystem that solve logistics data business needs. I work closely with stakeholders and lead the technical team to ensure that requirements and progress are captured accurately and communicated consistently.

GITHUB

SKILLS:

- SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server)
- Data Engineering Stack (Dagster, Meltano, Power BI, Superset, Azure Data Factory, Databricks)
- Azure development (Azure web app, Azure Devops)
- AWS development (Lambda with Python, S3, EC2, RDS, DynamoDB, etc.)
- Data Analysis with Python libraries (Pandas, Scikit-Learn, NumPy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, etc.)

EXPERIENCE

Feb 2022 - Present Software Engineer – Data at DuPont

- Serve as product owner for logistics data application with \$2 million of business value
- Communicate and realize evolving requirements from business stakeholders
- Lead technical team on application development
- Manage React Frontend, Python Fast API backend, SQL server database and Azure Devops

August 2021 – Feb 2022 Software Engineer – Data Scraping at Working Excellence

- Serve as a consulting engineer for a data service startup
- Contribute to overall platform pipeline architecture diagrams
- Create and maintain pipelines for dynamic web crawlers and scrapers
- Transform data for use in back-end web application API

August 2018 - Aug 2021

Python/Database Developer Freelance

- Create and manage PostgreSQL databases to store client's internal data
- Build web apps and APIs with Django
- Automate browsers to scrape information to fulfill client's data requests
- Build and document data pipelines

August 2014 – June 2021 Mathematics/Computer Science Teacher at Various Schools

- Provide instruction in Advanced Algebra and Computer Science
- Implement PostgreSQL and Python to analyze and track student data
- Serve as database manager for student grades and assignments

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

| July 2021 | AWS Certified Developer – Associate |
|--------------------|---|
| Jan 2021 | PCAP – Certified Associate in Python |
| Sep 2004- May 2009 | The College of New Jersey - Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics |